crowdsourcing.org 2018-12-25

# Privacy Policy

## Crowdsourcing, LLC Privacy Policy

Effective date: September 26, 2011.

The Website is © 2015 Crowdsourcing, LLC (hereinafter <>). The Website is the property of Crowdsourcing and Crowdsourcing grants you a limited license to access and use the Website pursuant to its Terms of Use Agreement.

Crowdsourcing may collect personal or personally identifiable information from you when you use the Website or when you participate in its associated services, including but not limited to your name, address, email address, date of birth, country, social networking profiles, website URL, IP address, geographical location, comments, links, posts, threads, feedback, and preferences while using the Website (collectively «Personal Information»).

 **Consent to Collect and Use Personal Information**

By submitting information to the Website, you manifest your assent to and agree to the terms contained within this Privacy Policy and its associated terms of use Agreement. Crowdsourcing will only collect Personal Information from you when you voluntarily provide such information through your use of the Website.

By providing any Personal Information to Crowdsourcing, you understand and agree that Crowdsourcing will collect and process your Personal Information in the United States and you provide your unequivocal consent to the collection and processing of your Personal Information in the United States.

 **Use of Personal Information**

Crowdsourcing may use Personal Information collected from you to provide you with the Website or its associated services, to provide other users with the Website or its associated services, to respond to requests that you have initiated, to improve the Website or its associated services, including but not limited to through Crowdsourcing’s analysis of usage patterns, and to communicate with you to update you on Crowdsourcing’s Website or services.

Crowdsourcing has adopted a Trusted Partners Program («Trusted Partners Program») that enables Crowdsourcing to provide its Trusted Partners («Trusted Partners») with analytics and market intelligence data, research insights, and other relevant information. Crowdsourcing determines the membership criteria of its Trusted Partners Program at its sole and absolute discretion, and Crowdsourcing will comply with all applicable local, state, and federal laws concerning the transfer of Personal Information when transferring Personal Information to its Trusted Partners. Crowdsourcing may provide your Personal Information to its Trusted Partners where Crowdsourcing determines that providing your Personal Information to its Trusted Partners would provide you with information or services that may be of interest to you or where Crowdsourcing determines that providing your Personal Information to its Trusted Partners would benefit Crowdsourcing, which will be determined in Crowdsourcing’s sole and absolute discretion.

Except as stated above, Crowdsourcing will not sell, rent, lease, or transfer your Personal Information to any individual, business, or government entity except to respond to duly authorized information requests by government authorities, to respond to a duly authorized court order or subpoena, to protect the officers, directors, employees, shareholders, or independent contractors of Crowdsourcing, or to help prevent against fraud or the violation of any applicable law, statute, regulation, ordinance, or treaty.

The Personal Information that your provide to Crowdsourcing, including but not limited to your email address, links to your social networking profiles, your country of origin, your website URL, and your selected avatar, may be displayed on your profile page, which may be accessible to all users of the Website. Additionally, your Personal Information, including but not limited to your comments, posts, and uploads, may be displayed on the Website, including on the Website’s news ticker, and may be viewed by third parties that access the Website.

Crowdsourcing may receive your Personal Information from other sources, including but not limited to third party websites that have contracted with Crowdsourcing. Crowdsourcing may also use this Personal Information pursuant to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

You understand and agree that Crowdsourcing is not responsible for any third party links, content, or communications sent to you from entities or individuals that Crowdsourcing does not own or control. You are advised to review the privacy policies of all third party websites.

 **Use of Cookies**

Crowdsourcing may collect Personal Information from you through the storage of data files on your computer called «cookies.» These cookies allow the Website to recognize your computer when you revisit the Website. Additionally, Crowdsourcing may collect Personal Information from you through the use of «session cookies,» which help Crowdsourcing track the pages that you visit during a single use of the Website and ensure that users are not required to re-enter their usernames and passwords upon accessing each page of the Website. These session cookies will expire once you leave the Website.

Your web browser may provide you with the ability to block or limit cookies. If you object to Crowdsourcing’s use of cookies, you are advised to adjust your web browser’s settings accordingly.

 **Tracking Techniques**

Crowdsourcing and its advertisers may collect Personal Information from you through the use of pixel tags, web beacons, or other tracking techniques. This Personal Information may be used for advertising purposes, whether contextual or otherwise, and may be shared with Crowdsourcing’s advertisers or with participants in Crowdsourcing’s Trusted Partners Program to provide advertisers and Trusted Partners with information on the demographics or preferences of the Website’s users.

 **Opt Out of Collection and Use of Personal Information**

Crowdsourcing provides you with the ability to opt-out of Crowdsourcing’s collection of your Personal Information by deleting your Member Account and by ceasing your use of the Website.

 **Crowdsourcing’s Sale or Purchase of a Business Unit or Subsidiary**

If Crowdsourcing acquires or sells a business unit or subsidiary, including but not limited to the complete sale of the Website to a third party, your Personal Information may be transferred to a third party. If this happens, your Personal Information will continue to be used consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

 **Protection and Storage of Personal Information**

Crowdsourcing undertakes commercially reasonable efforts to protect and secure your Personal Information. Crowdsourcing processes your Personal Information on computers located in the United States and has adopted procedural safeguards to protect against data theft. Crowdsourcing uses commercially standard and commercially reasonable encryption to ensure, to the extent possible, that your Personal Information is protected from unauthorized disclosure.

Should Crowdsourcing provide you with a Member Account, your Member Account may only be accessed through your entry of a username and password. You are advised not to share your Personal Information, including but not limited to your username and password, with any other person or entity.

Though Crowdsourcing takes the security of your Personal Information seriously, Crowdsourcing cannot guarantee that its servers and Website are complete secure. Crowdsourcing uses commercially reasonable efforts to protect your Personal Information, but you provide any and all Personal Information at your own risk.

 **Accuracy and Integrity of Personal Information**

You are responsible for ensuring that your Personal Information is accurate, complete, current, and relevant. You have an ongoing duty to inform Crowdsourcing of any changes in your Personal Information.

 **California Privacy Rights**

California residents have the right to receive information that identifies any third party companies or individuals that Crowdsourcing has shared your Personal Information with in the previous calendar year, as well as a description of the categories of Personal Information disclosed to that third party. You may obtain this information once a year and free of charge by contacting Crowdsourcing at [privacy@crowdsourcing.org](mailto:privacy@crowdsourcing.org).

 **Changes and Amendments**

Crowdsourcing reserves the right to amend, replace, or discontinue this Privacy Policy at any time. If Crowdsourcing changes or amends this Privacy Policy, the Effective Date of the Privacy Policy will change.

 **Contact and Notices**

All questions and concerns regarding this Privacy Policy may be directed to Crowdsourcing, LLC by emailing [privacy@crowdsourcing.org](mailto:privacy@crowdsourcing.org).
